Now that you've learned about conditional statements,
你已经学习了条件语句
let's move on to loops,
现在我们开始学习循环
which allow us to repeat blocks of code.
循环使我们能够重复一段代码
Python has two kinds,
Python 具有两种循环
for loops and while loops.
for 循环和 while 循环
Let's first take a look at the for loop,
我们先来看看 for 循环
which we can use to iterate over an iterable.
我们可以用 for 循环遍历可迭代的对象
An iterable is an object that can return one of its elements at a time.
可迭代对象是指每次可以返回一个元素的对象
This can include sequence types such as strings, lists,
包括字符串 列表和元组等序列类型
and tuples as well as non-sequenced types such as dictionaries and files.
以及字典和文件等非序列类型
You can define objects within iter method to allow them to be used as an iterable,
你可以使用 iter 方法定义对象 使其可以用作可迭代对象
which you can find more information on in the notes below.
更多信息请参阅下方的注释
Consider this for loop that iterates through a list of cities,
这段 for 循环会遍历一个城市列表
capitalizes each one, and prints it.
使每座城市首字母大写 然后输出这些城市
The for keyword signals that this is a for loop.
关键字 for 表示这是个 for 循环
Cities is the iterable and city is the loop's iteration variable.
Cities 是可迭代对象 city 是该循环的迭代变量
That is the variable that represents the element
该变量表示循环当前处理的
in the iterable that the loop is currently processing.
可迭代对象中的元素
So, in the first iteration,
因此 在第一次迭代时
city would be New York City.
city 是 new york city
In the second iteration,
在第二次迭代时
it would be Mountain View,and so on.
city 是 mountain view 以此类推
We can use the city variable to refer to an element
我们可以使用变量 city 表示在任何迭代期间
within the indented body of a for loop during any iteration.
for 循环的缩进主体中的一个元素
This indented body is executed once for each element in cities.
cities 中的每个元素都会执行一遍这个缩进的代码段
You can name iteration variables however you
你可以随意命名迭代变量
like though this example demonstrates a common pattern.
但是这个示例演示了一种常见模式
The name of the list cities is the plural form of city,
列表名称 cities 是 city 的复数形式
the name of the iteration variable.
city 是迭代变量的名称
Naming lists and iteration variables in this style makes it
按照这种方式命名列表和迭代变量
easier for other programmers to understand the purpose of each variable.
使其他程序员更容易明白每个变量的目的
So far, the loops we've written extract information from lists.
到目前为止 我们所写的循环都是从列表中提取信息
We can also use for loops to create lists and to modify lists.
我们还可以使用 for 循环创建列表和修改列表
To create a new list,
为了创建新的列表
we can start with an empty list,
我们可以从空列表开始
and then use the append method to add new items.
然后使用方法 append() 添加新项
This for loop iterates through each city and cities and appends it to capitalized cities.
这个 for 循环会遍历 cities 中的每座城市 并添加到首字母大写的 cities 中
Modifying a list is a bit more involved and requires a use of a new function, range.
修改列表稍微难一些 需要使用一个新的函数 叫做 range()
Range is a built in function used to create immutable sequences of numbers.
range() 是一个内置函数 用来创建不可变的数字序列
It has three arguments which must all be integers;
它有三个参数 必须全是整数
start, stop, and step.
分别是 start stop 和 step
Start is the first number of the sequence.
start 是序列的第一个数字
Stop is one above the last number of the sequence.
stop 是序列最后一个数字之前的数字
And step is the difference between the numbers in the sequence.
step 是序列中每个数字之间的差
If unspecified, start defaults to zero and step defaults to one.
如果未指定的话 start 默认为 0 step 默认为 1
Calling range with one integer will make that the stop argument and
如果调用 range() 并传入一个整数 将使该整数变成 stop 参数
return a sequence of numbers from zero to that integer minus one.
并返回一个从 0 开始到该整数减一的序列
So, range four returns zero through four minus one, which is three.
因此 range(4) 返回一个 0 到 4-1 即 3 的序列
Calling range with two integers will make those the start and stop,
如果调用 range() 并传入两个整数 将使这两个整数变成 start 和 stop 参数
and return a sequence of numbers from the first number to the second number minus one.
返回一个从第一个数字开始到第二个数字减一的序列
Range two, six returns a sequence from two to five.
range(2,6) 返回一个从 2 到 5 的序列
Calling range with three integers will return a sequence of numbers
如果调用 range() 并传入三个整数
from the first to the second minus one separated by the third.
将返回从第一个整数到第二个整数减一并用第三个整数划分的序列
So, range 1, 10,
因此 range(1,10,2)
2 returns a sequence from one to nine incremented by two.
返回一个从 1 到 9 并按 2 递增的序列
Notice in these examples,
注意 在这些示例中
we adopt range in a list before printing it.
我们先将 range() 封装在列表中 然后输出它
This is because printing just the output of range only shows you a range object.
因为直接输出 range 的结果将只显示 range 对象
You can view the values in the range object by
你可以通过将 range 对象转换为列表
converting it to a list or iterating through it in a for loop.
或用 for 循环遍历它来查看其中的值
Back in our cities example,
回到 cities 示例
we can use the range function to generate the indices of each value in the cities list.
我们可以使用函数 range() 生成 cities 列表中每个值的索引
This let's us access the elements of the list with cities bracket index.
这样使得我们能够使用 cities 括号索引访问该列表的元素
So, that we can modify the values in the cities list in place.
这样就可以直接修改 cities 列表中的值
Let's go through one iteration of this to
我们迭代一次
show exactly how all these pieces work together.
看看一切是如何运行的
Len cities provides four,
len(cities) 结果为 4
so the list will be a range from zero to three.
因此该列表的范围将是从 0 到 3
The index will take on each of these values one at a time.
索引将每次设为其中一个值
So, in this first iteration,
在第一次迭代时
we'll have an index of zero.
索引为 0
This part here will then index the first city, New York City,
这部分然后将对第一座城市（new york city）设定索引
capitalize it using title,
使用 title() 使其首字母大写
then place it back in place of the original New York City spot.
然后放在原始 new york city 的位置
This same process would then occur for each of the additional cities.
然后对剩下的每座城市执行相同的流程
We can use print to see the change in the cities list at each iteration.
我们可以使用 print() 查看在每次迭代时 cities 列表的变化
By getting a list of indices with the range function,
通过使用 range() 函数获得索引列表
we were able to index into each element of a list in a for loop to apply a change.
我们能够在 for 循环中对列表的每个元素设置索引 从而应用更改
While this modification is one application of the range function,
这种修改是函数 range() 的一种应用
that isn't the only thing it's useful for.
但是它并非只有这一个用途
You will frequently use range to repeat an action a certain number of times.
你将经常使用 range() 重复某个操作一定的次数